## Oleg Markov

087 418 2236 – <u>omarkov79@gmail.com</u> 38 Newcastle Manor Square – Newcastle – D22XD29

### **Summary**

I am an experienced and qualified facilities assistant, coordinator and building manager within property management and the Gaming & Technology industry. I have a proven history of various skills including Project Management, Administration, Health and Safety, Building Maintenance, Front Office Management, Budgeting, Event Planning, Customer Service, and Teamwork. My experience shows I am a highly skilled management professional who is able to deliver a gold-standard service in any role I undertake.

## **Relevant Employment History**

### Sep 2019 – Present HWBC/PMAL (property management advisors limited)

### **Position: Building Manager**

I started to work during the final stage of 7 million construction/investment project. I managed the takeover from builder/fit-out contractors of all mechanical and electrical equipment including the live supporting systems which included fire and intruder alarms, CCTV, access control, BMS, and AC control software.

I also managed the post-construction snag list and all the adjustments required afterwards in addition to organising the tender for the electrical, mechanical, and landscape maintenance services to get the best service and value for the money.

# **Responsibilities:**

- Management of all elements of day-to-day maintenance within the property.
- Administration management
- Delivered all building maintenance and statutory inspection services
- Delivered several maintenance projects (PPM and RM) in 2019-2022, ensuring the highest standards of health and safety, service quality, cost, and time management
- Management of vendor relationships
- Manage and support contractors to ensure they deliver the highest quality of work/service, value for money, and H&S standards to achieve Key Performance Indicators.
- Observation and Management of BMS, AC control software, CCTV, Access Control, Fire alarm.
- Liaising with the Property management agent, Landlords, and Clients

Nov 2010 - Oct 2017 Rational FT Services Limited

**Position: Facilities Coordinator** 

I assisted the office manager with over 350 employees working onsite in a 35000-square foot facility. My role was to assist with daily building facility management issues & projects. I was also responsible to oversee all outsourced vendor work carried out on-site to ensure a professional service was completed. I directed external maintenance staff as well as internal housekeeping and security vendors in addition to administrative tasks of the front desk. Completed multiple fit-out and refurbishment projects.

### **Duties:**

- Organized day to day reactive and planned preventative maintenance
- Carried out Office health and safety daily inspections including fire tours and risk assessments
- Assisted in new employee Onboarding including seating setup and DSE assessments etc.
- Supply chain management & stock control
- Acted as a site cover for the Workplace Operations Manager
- Management of office seating charts/floor maps and updates.
- Assisted internal office relocations
- Managed the contract cleaning company to ensure high standards were kept
- Room preparation for all in-house meetings including room merge to maximize space, and general office support as needed.
- Reported cleaning audits, spacewalks, maintenance walks
- Corresponded with contractors and suppliers providing facilities services
- Light furniture assembly/some heavy lifting MHS (manual handling assessment) training.
- Covered front desk and administration duties including greeting guests, making appointments, developing schedules, answering customer inquiries, handling correspondence, doing paperwork, and maintaining a professional image, Microsoft Office usage, IPOS system
- Facilitated Event planning

### Jan 2009-Sept 2010 Cagney Maintenance Services

### **Duties:**

- Responsible for crew monitoring
- Performance of Deep office cleaning, including canteen and relaxation areas
- Maintenance of various fridge's, Coffee machines, and vending machine stock
- Liaising with Client & Cleaning managers on daily basis.

#### **Education:**

- Covid 19 Response Manager/Lead Worker Representative Training
- IOSH Health and Safety for the leading personnel
- Awareness of Health and Safety & Facilities Management
- IBFM course
- VDU assessment training
- MHS manual handling assessment training
- High school 1985-1997

### Languages:

• Native: Russian

• Advanced in; English, Italian, Polish, Lithuanian